Hey everybody. My name is Dane Frederiksen.
I am a B2B video expert,
and I'm here today with Todd Fairbairn,
who is from Emotiv Mobility,
and we're here to talk about what's going on
in this crazy world of marketing and AI
and all the things we need to be thinking
about right now.
Todd, why don't you introduce yourself and
tell us a little bit about what we need to know about you.
Dane, thank you so much for having me on.
Todd Fairbairn —
I am Head of Marketing and Brand
at Emotiv Mobility.
It's a really interesting time to be in our space.
B2B marketing is always a challenge.
You've got to cut through the noise.
But I think you throw in AI
and everything that's happening,
and for brand folks on usually smaller teams,
you've got to leverage AI.
But how do you do it in a way that's authentic,
true to the brand, and isn't just slop?
It's a great tool,
but you've got to be responsible with it.
It's such a great moment to be having
this conversation. AI just took all the air
out of the room. We all went nuts last year,
made all this slop —
word of the year. Now I'm seeing the pendulum
swing back the other way.
They're hiring content writers to be human again.
There's finally some appreciation
for the work that we do, and it has real value
beyond just hitting numbers with volume.
So when that meets actual practice —
how are you using AI, or not using it?
What's top of mind for you?
We use it a fair bit, in full transparency.
It's not our North Star,
nor does it help us get there. But we use it
to gut check a lot of our activities.
My marketing team — we're a smaller B2B
in the automotive space.
It's myself, I have a marketing performance
and operations manager who leads our campaigns,
and then I have a content creator
who's diving into the material.
AI for us — we use it for keeping our website
content fresh, looking at what others
in the space are doing, and guiding us
on blog posts, thinking about keywords.
We'd love to see how we can use tools
from a video content perspective.
That is real intriguing for a smaller group.
How can we get more with less?
But then use it with the diligence
and responsibility of remaining true to the brand.
This is one of my goals with this interview series —
to take the chocolate and the peanut butter
and put them together. Me as a video expert,
you as a marketer with your expertise.
I'm always advocating for leveraging video
in an authentic way that still lets you
use AI responsibly without diluting your brand.
I think the best term for it is
video-first content marketing.
The idea is that video, because it contains
all other formats, is the perfect raw ingredient
for a content system that's repeatable
and ongoing.
Imagine an interview like this chopped up
into shorts, take the transcript,
use that for written content. If you plan that
ahead of time rather than repurposing
as an afterthought — I call it pre-purposing.
Planning ahead, building a system
that's low-lift.
SMEs shouldn't be writing articles,
especially in this day and age.
An interview like this is a great way
to extract on-brand thought leadership
and repurpose it across all channels.
There's this idea that so many different levels
of quality are acceptable now.
A scrappy iPhone video or a webcam video
like this has value if the content is valuable
and it's used in the right way, in the right place.
Of course, polished brand videos
and Super Bowl commercials have their place too.
But post-pandemic, social media world —
there's this other lane
that B2B is just now waking up to.
I love where your head's at, Dane.
Sometimes you never have enough time
to tackle these ideas.
From your perspective, it's almost like
a grand campaign where you have longer form
content and you break it down
and leverage it across a multitude
of different facets.
That was a big driving principle
while I was at Ford Motor Company.
And what I think is so fun — for so long,
B2B has been kind of rigid, no personality.
There's a hesitancy for brands to step out
and be their own identity.
There's a lot of hiding. It's the people,
the humanity, that makes a huge impact
as a brand differentiator.
It's one of the things we've been looking at doing.
How might we get the individuals
on an assembly line at one of our facilities
to capture the actual pieces coming together —
an activity that 99% of people
wouldn't normally see.
But there are so many supply chain companies
touching that product. It's really cool moments.
The biggest opportunity for brands in our space
is to flex about the people doing the work.
Everyone's sitting on a content goldmine,
because you do have the subject matter experts,
the people doing the work. There's this idea
of hiding behind white papers and ghost writing.
The marketplace has started to demand
something different.
A lot of execs are being asked to take off
the mask and be real. And it makes people uncomfortable.
So what I'm getting closer to now is finding ways
people can say yes.
The grand master plan content strategy
just sounds too big, too hard.
How can we start small?
Let's give this a pilot project name.
Let's call this a test. Making it so the bar
is low and you can get some reps in.
A lot of people don't want to be on camera.
If you can make that less scary —
let's just record something and not post it.
We'll look at it, talk about it,
and then maybe take another swing.
I think there are paths forward
in either direction.
The beauty of my job is I get to try
different things.
People in my space haven't done it before.
Doesn't mean it's wrong.
Doesn't mean it's right. You don't really know
until you give it a whirl.
Making this part of some grandiose annual
strategic marketing plan —
that just sounds daunting and not fun.
Everybody in marketing, we're in it to build
things we love to see.
I love incremental approaches.
Let's try this.
We flirted with the idea of TikTok
while at CES. That was interesting.
When we were at CES, that's where the audience was.
It would be prudent to be there.
You have to give things the opportunity
before you automatically dismiss them.
Everything we've known has kind of flipped
on its head in the past 10 years.
That's the beauty and the frustration
of our space.
How are you selling this "we've got to just
try it" mentality to people who need ROI,
numbers, results? How do you balance the need
to measure with the need to test?
It is a balancing act,
and that's the most stressful part.
We'll do little pilot-type programs where it's
a piece of a smaller underlying budget.
We let the core piece of the business
carry the mail, then we see what kind of reaction
these little pilots cause.
If you string a couple together
over a couple of quarters,
then you might be on to something.
Then it's easier to convince leadership
that this is something we try
a little bit more in subsequent years.
It's these incremental, anecdotal tries
to see where we might connect.
If we're on to something,
then we keep pushing until we crack the egg
or start from scratch.
As you're looking forward — what are the things
in front of you? What's the next thing
for you, or for the industry?
Where are we headed?
I think AI, in terms of being able
to harness it — one of my marketing leads
has been all over Claude for the past
couple of weeks, figuring out how to leverage it
better for what we're doing.
I do think there's going to continue to be
a movement to have people telling the story,
focusing on individuals to write copy,
because there are differences.
You can tell things are AI-written
versus an actual individual.
That delicate balance will continue to be there.
It's been a wild 12 months.
It's probably going to be a wild 24 months
as these tools continue to get smarter.
We as marketers have a responsibility
to be good stewards of the tools,
leverage them in a way that's beneficial
for our craft.
Whether it's HubSpot or other platforms
pushing AI functionality —
you're just inundated with AI everywhere.
That'll be fascinating to see
how these capabilities all connect
and intertwine.
It's the wild west all over again.
Todd, thanks for joining me today.
Great conversation.
Good luck out there.
Absolutely. Dane, appreciate the time. Cheers.